Julio Perdiguer Ordóñez

+34 635 46 53 18 | julio.perdiguer@gmail.com

Summary

Well qualified full stack developer, familiar with a wide range of programming utilities and expertise in PHP, Python and Javascript and experience in good architecture practices such as Microservices, DDD, SOLID and clean code. Handles any part of the process with ease. Collaborative team player with excellent technical abilities offering more than 10 years of experience.

Objective

A backend position in a company that owns a product where quality and good practices are more important than hasty delivering, having capacity to make decisions and contribute with ideas about architecture and even the possibility to lead a small team of devs.

Experience

December 2022- current

Senior backend developer | Signa Sports United | Remote

Built a translation hub in DDD to be used for the whole company, also working in maintenance tickets in the old monolithic system and developing functionalities for a new PIM system on top of Riversand.

Tech stack and architecture: PHP 7.2, PHP 8.2, Symfony, Vue, AWS, Docker, DDD, microservices, Riversand

January 2022 – December 2022

Senior backend developer | Mad collective | Remote

Contributing to build the new microservices architecture for the billing department and at the same time maintenance and development of new requirements in the old legacy monolith. Also solving devops tasks.

Tech stack and architecture: PHP 5.6, PHP 8, Symfony, nodejs, AWS, Terraform, Docker, Circleci, DDD, microservices

February 2019 – December 2021

Senior full stack developer and CTO | Borax | Barcelona

Migration of the legacy monolith to a better microservices architecture. Creation of a new full frontend interface built in Vue.js. Leading the company's tech decisions, improving performance and reduce logistic costs with technical improvements in the company's audit software.

Tech stack and architecture: PHP 7.2, Python, Django, Django REST Framework, Docker, DDD, microservices

June 2016 - January 2019

Founder and senior full stack developer | Anyma.io | Barcelona

Leading a small consultancy company of 4 employees managing and delivering multiple projects for different customers.

Tech stack and architecture: PHP 5.6, PHP 7, Javascript, Symfony, PHPCake, Yii 2, Drupal 7, Drupal 8, Ionic, Prestashop

September 2015 - May 2016

Mid full stack developer | Freelance | Barcelona

September 2013 – August 2015

Mid full stack developer | Würth IT | Baden Wuttemberg

Maintenance and development of new requirements of the company CMS.

Tech stack and architecture: PHP, First Spirit CMS (Java based), Javascript, Symfony, Sylex

September 2012 – August 2013

Mid full stack developer | FHIOS smart knowledge | Barcelona

IT consulting

Tech stack and architecture: PHP, Javascript, Drupal 6, Drupal 7, Joomla, Wordpress, Magento, Prestashop

September 2011 – August 2012

Junior full stack developer | Offerum | Barcelona

Groupon-like project. Task resolution and participation in development of new functionalities

Tech stack and architecture: PHP, Javascript, Code Igniter

September 2010 – September 2011

Internship as web developer | Telefonica R&D | Barcelona

Participation in a variety of interesting projects, mentored by other senior developers who introduced me into the basics of web dev, learning Drupal, Jquery and Zend framework.

Tech stack and architecture: PHP, Drupal, javascript, Zend

Education

University of Barcelona
Bachelor of computer engineering | Finished June 2011

Technical knowledge

- Programming languages: PHP, Javascript, Python, MySQL
- PHP frameworks: Symfony, Zend, Codelgniter, Yii2, PHP Cake
- Python frameworks: Django, FastAPI
- Javascript Frameworks: Angular, Vue, Babylon
- Mobile development frameworks: lonic
- Ecommerce and CMS: Prestashop, Magento, Wordpress, Drupal
- DevOps: Docker, Terraform, AWS, CircleCl
- Transversal knowledge: SOLID, DDD, TDD, clean code, Microservices

Certifications

• AWS Cloud Practicioner – 2022

Hobbies and interests

- Culture: Videogames, films and rock music
- Sports: Playing basketball, martial arts and running
- Interests: Geopolitics, history, liquid democracy, human rights, technology, sustainability